LUIZ RENNÓ COSTA

tensorflow

Data Scientist | Data Engineer | Machine Learning Engineer

@ luizrennocosta@gmail.com

J +5521-99364-4383

Rio de Janeiro, Brazi

in luiz-rennó-costa

sklearn

Iuizrennocosta

STRENGTHS

Python pandas numpy numpy

keras

Data Wrangling (ETL/ELT)

ML Pipelines ML Modelling

Docker Kubernetes

SQL/NoSQL (Airflow

PySpark Hadoop

GCP Firebase Dataproc

Git Linux

LEARNING

Deep Learning pytorch

Reinforced Learning

Audio Processing

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Native

English: Fluent

REFERENCES

Tech Leaders

- in Victor Redivo
- in Fulvio Neto
- in Felipe de Albuquerque

Teammates

in Aline Goulart

in Fabio Valonga

ABOUT ME

Hello, I'm Luiz, a MSc in Electrical Engineering focused on Machine Learning research, currently working on the Data Engineering field on a quest to become a full-fledged specialist on the Data and Machine Learning fields. I enjoy tough challenges and thinking outside the box in order to solve them.

EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer | Data Scientist | Loft

= 02/2022 - 03/2023

Remote

- Refined the team's entire code structure, improving performance and code/ML reproducibility.
- Improved several ETLs by optimizing queries, PySpark code and table partitioning.
- Worked together with other engineering teams to map and define multiple improvement points for the entire Data Chapter.
- Researched and implemented a StableDiffusion-based application to "decorate" apartment photos.
- Created a XGBoost-based model to predict buyer's visit-scheduling probability across time.
- Created and maintained multiple interactive data-viz prototypes using Streamlit and ML Models for the Business Intelligence area.
- Defined and deployed multiple model APIs to production through a SageMaker layer alongside the MLOps team.

Substitute Teacher | Federal University of Rio de Janeiro

1 03/2023 - Present

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

• Teach Electronics and Computing (Python 101) classes

Data Engineer | Data Scientist | Dextra Consulting

12/2020 - 02/2022

Remote

- Creation of text-processing PySpark jobs for multiple client pipelines on a lakehouse architecture.
- Design and implementation of a Highly Available infrastructure of a Speech-to-Text and text-processing project using GCP (Dataproc, R-MIG, Compute Engine, Firebase, Cloud Function, Build and Run).
- Support and development of machine learning models for sentiment analysis.
- Contributed for the creation of several PySpark jobs for multiple text-processing pipelines for different clients on a lakehouse architecture.

Data Engineer | Samsung Electronics

1 01/2020 - 09/2020

Campinas, Brazil

- Data extraction procedure automation using a distributed architecture with Apache Airflow and Docker.
- Creation of spark jobs for data indexing and logging of metadata.



Honorable Mention

Prize awarded for the 5 finalists (of over 1000) students at the 7th Week of Academic Integration at UFRJ



Hackathon Winner

Winner of the first Hackathon hosted at **UFRJ**



The courses included:

- Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- Structuring Machine **Learning Projects**
- Convolutional Neural Networks
- Sequence Models

Published Articles

- Medical Engineering & Physics
- · Research in Nondestructive Evaluation
- ABM Proceedings
- IFAC-PapersOnLine

- **CHIEVEMENTS** Relational database architecture and modeling for event logging.
 - General automation of procedures and ETLs using Bash, Python, and Docker.
 - Development of database-interface APIs using NodeJS.

Data Scientist | Grupo SOMA

1 07/2019 - 12/2019

- Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
- Implementation of a cluster using Kubernetes (GKE) for the orchestration of dockerized ETLs in Python.
- Creation of a scalable development platform used for several projects using Jupyter Hub hosted in a cluster with Kubernetes.
- Development of a workshop on data science, machine learning models and their applications.
- Implementation of a supervised model to predict sales of new products based on historical data and visual characteristics, with direct development on the whole machine learning chain, from data processing to serving the model through a REST API using Flask.
- Establishment of a work flow to analyze and compare machine learning models using MLFlow.

Masters Scholarship | COPPETEC

i 03/2017 - 03/2019

- Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
- Development of an autonomous system for defect propagation monitoring based on acoustic emission on rigid pipes

Academic Internship | Biomedical Engineering Program - UFRJ

2016 - 2017

- Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
- Research in applied control for bio medicine, with a focus on the rehabilitation of patients with Spasticity.

EDUCATION

MSc. in Electrical Engineering | Federal University Of Rio de Janeiro

= 03/2017 - 04/2019

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

- GPA: 2.88/3.0 (A)
- Study and research on applied machine learning techniques and models for a project in the Oil and Gas industry in colaboration with PETROBRAS.

BSc. in Electronics and Computer Engineering | Federal University Of Rio de Janeiro

i 03/2013 - 03/2019

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

GPA: 8.3/10.0